Typically when we talk about data transfer efficiency, we're talking
about limiting the amount of data being transferred. That reduces
the bandwidth and the cost and is generally a pretty
good idea. But on mobile there's an extra factor. As you
can see, it turns out that the cell radio is
one of the biggest battery drainers on the device. So making
your data transfers more efficient. Will also result in improved
battery life. Now, the basic level being more efficient means spending
less time transferring less data, reducing your payloads, and updating
less often can take you some of the way there,
but then what? Can timing make a difference? It turns
out that it can, and it's a situation I like
to think of as the cookie Droid conundrum. Do we
perform fewer downloads with larger payloads? Or do we perform
lots of small transfers just in time for when we
need them? One big cookie or lots of little cookies?
So, what do you think? Should we have
a smaller number of large downloads illustrated by
this big cookie? Or a large number of
small downloads, as illustrated by lots of little cookies.